Guide to the Local Newspapers on Microfilm Collection BCMS.0028
Brooklyn Collection
Local Newspapers on Microfilm Collection
1835-1999
Brooklyn Collection
BCMS.0028
220 Linear Feet
This collection consists of 89 Brooklyn-based newspapers on microfilm. These newspapers contain local news in specific neighborhoods as well as borough, city, and national news.
Related Materials
Brooklyn Ephemera Collection (BCMS.0007): Our ephemera collection includes issues of a number of local newsletters, newspapers, and other periodicals.
Brooklyn High School Newspaper Collection (BCMS.0030)
World War I political cartoons collection (CBHM.0011)
Brooklyn Newsstand: Over 40 papers from this collection digitized and keyword-searchable online.
Scope and Contents
The Local Newspapers on Microfilm Collection consists of 89 neighborhood and Brooklyn-wide newspapers covering the years 1835-1999. Each of the papers, varying widely in scope of coverage, generally includes information on politics, business, education, church events, sports, entertainment, and community happenings. Some papers provide coverage of international events while others are exclusively devoted to events in Brooklyn. Since no two papers are identical in scope the individual descriptions should be consulted to discover the precise contents of each paper.
After the Brooklyn Daily Eagle ceased operations in 1955, Brooklyn was left without a single comprehensive news source covering life in Brooklyn. Because of this, this collection is an invaluable resource for discovering information about the borough. In addition to articles on daily life, many of the papers in the collection also contain obituaries, wedding notices, and birth announcements – providing a useful resource for researchers looking for genealogical traces beyond 1955. In addition to its usefulness as a genealogical tool, the collection also provides a window into immigrant communities; the collection includes newspapers devoted to Norwegian, Finnish, Syrian, Lebanese, Lithuanian, and Russian communities. Papers devoted to covering Jewish communities as well as African-American communities are also included in the collection.
Please note that the date range 1835-1999 does not represent continuous coverage but rather reflects the earliest date and the latest date covered. Likewise, not every neighborhood is covered during every year of that date range. Refer to the individual descriptions to discover the dates for any given neighborhood newspaper.
Access
Open to users without restriction.
Newspapers
- Bay News, 1958-1999; 179 Reels (Bin 1, Bin 2, Bin 3, Bin 4)
  Scope and Contents
  Largely focusing on the Sheepshead Bay community, Bay News provides local coverage of politics, business events, school happenings, sporting events, and church news. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and death notices, though not receiving a dedicated section, do appear occasionally in the paper.
- Bay Ridge Courier, 1985-1993; 38 Reels (Bin 5)
  Largely focusing on the communities of Sheepshead Bay, Bay Ridge, and Bensonhurst, the Bay Ridge Courier provides local news coverage in business, schools, arts and leisure, sports, churches, and politics. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and death notices rarely appear in the pages of the newspaper. There is no formal obituary section. The Bay Ridge Courier includes numerous profiles of local businesses and business leaders. Photographs appear throughout, as do advertisements for local businesses.
- Bay Ridge Home Reporter, 1954-1962; 5 Reels (Bin 5)
  General
  This title is available digitally on Brooklyn Newsstand. The title is also available via your or your library's paid subscription to Newspapers.com.
  Largely focusing on the neighborhood of Bay Ridge, with later issues covering the neighborhoods of Bensonhurst and Park Slope, the Bay Ridge Home Reporter and Sunset News provides coverage of local politics, business, sports, religion, education, and community news. Obituaries and marriage announcements regularly appear.
- Bay Ridge Home Reporter and Sunset News, 1962-1966; 117 Reels (Bin 19, Bin 20, Bin 21, Bin 22)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhood of Bay Ridge, with later issues covering the neighborhoods of Bensonhurst and Park Slope, the Bay Ridge Home Reporter and Sunset News provides coverage of local politics, business, sports, religion, education, and community news. Obituaries and marriage announcements regularly appear. Issues from 1977 include in-depth coverage of the Son of Sam murders. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Bay Ridge Paper, 1994-1999; 5 Reels (Bin 5)
  Providing general coverage of Brooklyn with an emphasis on the neighborhoods of Bay Ridge and Bensonhurst, the Bay Ridge Paper provides some political, education, business, and community news. However, personal ads, classifieds, and advertisements for local businesses comprise most of the paper's content. Obituaries, wedding announcements, and birth announcements do not appear. Photographs appear throughout. Police reports are also regularly published.
- Beach Journal, 1979-1980; 1 Reels (Bin 4)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of Brighton Beach, Coney Island, and Manhattan Beach, the Beach Journal provides coverage of business, political, education, and community news, with an emphasis on the area's Jewish community. Engagement announcements as well as Bat and Bar Mitzvah announcements regularly appear. Advertisements, classifieds, and photographs appear throughout. Stories about the area's Russian immigrant population also regularly appear.
- Big Red News, 1982-1992; 13 Reels (Bin 6)
  Big Red News provides city-wide coverage of African-American issues and happenings. The paper is international in scope with an emphasis on Africa, particularly events in South Africa. Business, religious, entertainment, community, and city-wide sports news are all regularly covered. Classifieds, personals, and advertisements appear throughout, as do photographs. There are no dedicated sections for obituaries, weddings, or birth announcements, though death notices for prominent African-Americans occasionally appear. Some issues include a "Black Business Directory" listing local businesses. Later issues include a page called "Big Red Poetry" where the poems of local residents are published. A page called "Lottomania" also appears in later issues, featuring lists of lucky numbers as well as number games.
- Brooklyn Affairs, 1984-1985; 1 Reels (Bin 6)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhood of Park Slope as well as the surrounding Prospect Park area, Brooklyn Affairs is principally a community paper devoted to arts and culture issues--covering everything from Brooklyn architecture and sculpture to arts and crafts for children. As a result, the paper does not provide typical news coverage. Book reviews, health and well-being, and pet and nature sections all appear regularly, as do comic strips created by local residents. Obituaries, wedding announcements, and birth announcements do not appear in the paper. Photographs and advertisements appear throughout.
- Brooklyn Baron, 1997; 1 Reels (Bin 6)
  Largely focusing on news in around the neighborhoods of Bergen Beach and Coney Island, the Brooklyn Baron provides coverage of events in greater Brooklyn as well. Dining and entertainment, health and fitness, education, sports--both amateur and professional--and financial and business news are all regularly covered. A law section also appears regularly and includes editorials by prominent New York politicians. Obituaries, wedding announcements, and birth announcements do not appear.
- Brooklyn Citizen, 1887-1947; 212 Reels (Case D4 cabinets)
  The Brooklyn Citizen provides Brooklyn-wide coverage of business, education, arts and culture, sports, religion, and entertainment news. Some national and international coverage of news events is provided as well. Early issues of the paper include numerous stories regarding labor and union issues in Brooklyn. Early issues also include "Death Notices" and "Marriage Notices" while later issues of the paper have sections dedicated to both obituaries and wedding announcements. Birth announcements do not appear regularly. Sunday editions are heavily illustrated and include such sections as: "In the Realm of Woman," "Ward Gossip," "Amateur Stage," and "Truly a City of Churches," covering fashion, neighborhood news, theater, and religion, respectively. Later issues often contain many photographs. Comics appear throughout the run of the paper, as do advertisements.
- Brooklyn Courier, 1978-1985; 22 Reels (Bin 6, Bin 7)
  Largely focusing on the neighborhoods of Bay Ridge, Flatbush, Brighton Beach, and Coney Island, the Brooklyn Courier provides coverage of local politics, business, sports, education, and arts and culture news. News from Kingsborough Community College is also regularly featured. Classifieds and personals appear throughout, as do photographs and advertisements. Obituaries, wedding announcements, and birth announcements do not appear in the paper. A feature called "Courier Art Gallery" featuring the art work of local residents also appears regularly.
- Brooklyn Daily, 1956-1963; 41 Reels (Case Morgue microfilm shelves)
  The Brooklyn Daily provides coverage of political, business, education, arts and culture, sports, and community news for the entire borough of Brooklyn. National and international news coverage is also provided. A section called "In the Neighborhoods" provides neighborhood by neighborhood coverage of events, business promotions, hirings, graduations, meetings, and happenings. Wedding and engagement announcements appear as part of a "Social Notes" section. Birth announcements appear regularly in a "Brooklyn Babies" column. There is also a section dedicated to obituaries. The sports page provides consistent Dodgers coverage. A column entitled, "Glamour Corner" covers fashion and beauty trends in the borough.
- Brooklyn Daily Bulletin, 1970-1984, 1995-1996; 51 Reels (Bin 7, Bin 8)
  The Brooklyn Daily Bulletin provides Brooklyn-wide coverage of business, legal, civic, sports, and political news. Neither birth nor wedding notices appear. Death announcements for prominent Brooklynites appear in early issues. However, there is no section devoted to obituaries. Announcements of appointments, business honors, and promotions also appear. Advertisements appear throughout, and are increasingly present in later issues. Later issues also contain a large section entitled "Brooklyn Business Journal."
- Brooklyn Daily Times, 1855-1932; 1006 Reels; This collection is missing reels for 1855, 1857, January-June 1867, November-December 1869, July-December 1872, and August-September 1900. (Case Morgue microfilm shelves)
  Largely focusing on the Eastern District – the neighborhoods of Bushwick, Williamsburg, and Ridgewood – the Brooklyn Daily Times provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, religion, arts, culture, sports, and entertainment. Early issues of the paper consist mainly of advertisements accompanied by a few local news items. In later issues of the paper the news coverage is expanded and photographs appear. Regularly appearing columns include: "Among German Societies," "Doings of the War Veterans," "The Fraternal Orders," "Books and Writers," and "The Religious World." Lists of marriage licenses and death notices occasionally appear. Birth notices do not appear in the paper. Advertisements appear throughout. Includes special editions such as the Long Island Edition, Wall Street Edition, Noon Edition and so forth. In March of 1932 the Brooklyn Daily Times merged with The Standard Union and both titles were on the masthead until June, when the paper was renamed the Brooklyn Times Union.
- Brooklyn Free Press, 1987-1990; 2 Reels (Bin 8)
  Largely focusing on the Park Slope area of Brooklyn, the Brooklyn Free Press provides local news coverage of arts, culture, education, health, and politics. Numerous articles appear in the paper covering local involvement in and reaction to events in Nicaragua concerning the Sandinista National Liberation Front—including opinion pieces as well as photo essays. A column called "Your Sexual Life" also regularly appears and addresses community concern over the AIDS epidemic. Films and art shows are reviewed regularly. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Advertisements appear throughout.
- Brooklyn Graphic, 1955-1999; 71 Reels; This collection is missing reels for the years 1986-1989. (Bin 8, Bin 9)
  The Brooklyn Graphic provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, arts, culture, entertainment and sports. Initially covering the neighborhoods of Brownsville, East New York, Crown Heights, and East Flatbush, later issues cover news in the neighborhoods of Bensonhurst, Bay Ridge, Brighton Beach, Manhattan Beach, and Coney Island. All coverage is specific to the Jewish populations in these areas. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper.
- Brooklyn Heights Courier, 1991-1993; 6 Reels (Bin 10)
  Largely focusing on the Brooklyn Heights and Downtown area, the Brooklyn Heights Courier provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, arts, culture, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. A section entitled "Business Brooklyn Style" regularly appears. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Brooklyn Heights Paper, 1984-1999; 11 Reels (Bin 10)
  Largely focusing on Brooklyn Heights, Downtown, and Carroll Gardens, the Brooklyn Heights Paper provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, arts, culture, sports and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. A section entitled "Special Brooklyn Progress Report" highlights building initiatives and neighborhood development. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Brooklyn Heights Press, 1939-1999; 49 Reels (Bin 13, Bin 36)
  This title's issues from 1961-1971 are available digitally on Brooklyn Newsstand. The content is also available via your or your library's paid subscription to Newspapers.com.
  Largely focusing on the Brooklyn Heights area, the Brooklyn Heights Press provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, arts, culture, religion, and entertainment. There is no dedicated obituary section, though death notices for prominent Brooklynites regularly appear. Wedding announcements occasionally appear, as do engagement announcements. News of happenings and events at various neighborhood clubs, organizations, and associations also appears regularly. A column written by a local pastor called "On the Spiritual Side" is regularly published, as are excerpts from the sermons of Brooklyn Heights clergymen. Later issues contain mainly arts and culture news, including coverage of lectures, theater performances, and art shows. In later issues, too, the name of the paper changes to Brooklyn Heights Press and Cobble Hill News.
- Brooklyn Life, 1890-1931; 54 Reels (Case Morgue microfilm drawers)
  Brooklyn Life magazine provides Brooklyn-wide news coverage of society, club life, theater, and politics. Some wedding announcements for prominent Brooklynites appear and, in later issues, a section devoted to death announcements appears. There are no birth announcements. Early issues of the paper are heavily illustrated and contain numerous proverbs, epigrams, aphorisms, and poems. Local club news covers the sports of cricket, badminton, tennis, and lacrosse. Often times entire issues are devoted to a single subject, such as: Bicycling, Easter, Horse Shows, Outings, Education, and St. Valentine's Day. Issues commonly include numerous photographs of life in Brooklyn. At the beginning of the 20th century a "Military" section appears in the paper, as does a "Motoring" section. Photographs of stage productions appear regularly in the paper. The names and addresses of "Automobile Owners of Brooklyn and Long Island" also appear regularly after the turn of the century. Advertisements appear throughout.
- Brooklyn Paper, 1979-1986; 6 Reels (Bin 10)
  Largely focusing on the areas of Park Slope, Carroll Gardens, Brooklyn Heights, and Red Hook, the Brooklyn Paper provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, arts, culture, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. However, the deaths of prominent community members are occasionally covered. The paper also features regular articles on brownstones and brownstone owners in the area, as well as a column called "Brownstone Parenting." Extensive coverage is also given to building developments in the area. Consistent coverage is also given to local reaction to U.S. involvement in Nicaragua. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Brooklyn Paper, Carroll Gardens-Cobble Hill, 1984-1989; 3 Reels (Bin 10)
  Largely focusing on the areas of Carroll Gardens, Cobble Hill, Brooklyn Heights, Boerum Hill, Red Hook, and Park Slope, the Brooklyn Paper--Carroll Gardens and Cobble Hill, provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, arts, culture, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. A regularly appearing section called, "Merchant Profiles" provides photographs and descriptions of many local businesses. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout. (See also: Carroll Gardens/Cobble Hill Courier & The Newspaper.)
- Brooklyn Record, 1953-1997; 28 Reels; The issues from 1994 are on a multi-year reel starting with June 1972. (Case Morgue microfilm drawers, Bin 13)
  Issues up to 1964 are available digitally on Brooklyn Newsstand. That content is also available via your or your library's paid subscription to Newspapers.com.
  Largely focusing on the areas of Bay Ridge and Flatbush, the Brooklyn Record provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, religion, and entertainment. Birth announcements and wedding announcements do not appear in the paper. However, engagement announcements and anniversary announcements occasionally appear in a section devoted to "Personal" announcements. A dedicated obituary section does appear in early issues of the paper but is absent in later issues. A section entitled "Jewish War Veteran Notes" regularly appears in the paper as does a more general "VFW Section." Consistent coverage is also given to events at area community colleges. Local clubs and organizations—such as the Elks and the Young Republican Club of Bay Ridge—are also covered. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Brooklyn Spectator, 1955-1996; 82 Reels (Bin 10, Bin 11, Bin 12)
  Largely focusing on Bay Ridge, Fort Hamilton, Dyker Heights, Bensonhurst, and Sunset Park, the Brooklyn Spectator provides local news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, religion, and entertainment. Early issues contain wedding announcements, with photos of brides, as well as engagement announcements. A section devoted to birth announcements also appears as does a death notices section. A "High School Notes" section provides news from area schools while "Service Notes" covers news of local residents serving in the military. Many issues contain photos of car accidents and accident scenes, often with images of critically injured or even dead drivers and passengers. In later issues birth notices and wedding announcements appear with less frequency, in a general "Social Notes" section. Advertisements and photographs appear throughout.
- Brooklyn Standard Union (The Standard Union), 1863-1932; 353 Reels (Case D4 cabinets)
  The Brooklyn Standard Union provides Brooklyn-wide news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, religion, and entertainment. International and national news coverage is also provided. Early issues do not contain birth announcements or wedding announcements. However, such announcements occasionally appear in later issues and a list of marriage licenses appears near the end of the paper's run. Death notices appear regularly in early issues of the paper while later issues contain an expanded obituary section. Issues from the early 20th century contain sections devoted to such neighborhoods as Greenpoint, Brownsville, East New York, and South Brooklyn. Advertisements appear throughout and photographs appear in later issues. In March of 1932 the Brooklyn Daily Times merged with The Standard Union and both titles were on the masthead until June, when the paper was renamed the Brooklyn Times Union.
- Brooklyn Star, 1971-1972; 1 Reels (Bin 12)
  The Brooklyn Star provides Brooklyn-wide news coverage of business, politics, religion, and community events. Birth announcements, weddings announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Regularly appearing columns include: "Women in Business," "Report from Boro Hall," and "Retirement Living in Florida." Advertisements appear throughout. Few photographs appear in the paper.
- Brooklyn Sunday Review, 1873-1874; 1 Reels (Case Morgue microfilm drawers)
  The Brooklyn Sunday Review provides Brooklyn-wide news coverage of art, music, drama, clubs and organizations, politics, religion, and literature. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Notices of daily church services appear regularly as does a column entitled "Weekly Review" which highlights the week's events in Brooklyn. A section called "Ladies Department" covers women's fashion and shopping news. A "Masonic" column provides news of Masonic meetings, rites, and ceremonies in and around the borough. Poems, short sketches, and stories are regularly published. Advertisements appear throughout.
- Brooklyn Sunday Star, 1927-1928; 1 Reels (Case Morgue microfilm drawers)
  Largely focusing on the areas of Bay Ridge, Flatbush, and South Brooklyn more generally, the Brooklyn Sunday Star provides news coverage of business, politics, education, community events, clubs and organizations, arts, culture, sports, religion, and entertainment. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries all appear regularly. Lists of births at particular hospitals also appear regularly. Some of the hospitals include: Methodist Episcopal, Shore Road, Norwegian Hospital, United Israel-Zion, and Borough Park Maternity Hospital, to name a few. Many photographs appear in the paper, covering sporting events, fashion, and social gatherings. Advertisements appear throughout.
- Brooklyn Sunday Sun, 1873-1876; 1 Reels (Case Morgue microfilm drawers)
  The Brooklyn Sunday Sun provides Brooklyn-wide news coverage of social events, arts, entertainment, culture, sports, military matters, politics, clubs and organizations, and religion. Some coverage is also given to national and state news. Birth announcements, wedding announcements, and obituaries do not appear in the paper. Editorials, society news, as well as music and drama reviews regularly appear in the paper. Advertisements appear throughout.
- Brooklyn Tablet (The Tablet), 1908-1985; 96 Reels (Bin 35)